GILBERT LANGAT

🗣 Nairobi, Kenya 🛮 🗷 gilbert@aims.ac.za 📞 (254)711170904 🔭 https://langatgilbert.github.io

A seasoned data professional specialized in delivering data-driven solutions in agric-tech, clean energy and fin-tech across Africa helping organization derive value and impact. Highly skilled product development process, data wrangling and visualization, and creative thinking.



Professional Experience

SuperFluid Labs

Associate Data Manager

02/2020 - present | Nairobi, Kenya

- · Lead a team of data analyst, scientists and engineers in ensuring client projects are delivered on time and per clients requirements.
- Lead liaison between data, product and business development teams to help ensure the customer and business insights platform is implemented to meet market demands.

Data Scientist

09/2018 - 01/2020 | Nairobi, Kenya

- Worked closely with product team to develop portfolio management and monitoring framework for a solar Paygo company. Reduced PAR-30 from 36% to 21%.
- Performed customer segmentation on pension contributors on a voluntary-based contribution scheme. This guided a data-driven customer engagement and targeting improving contribution behavior by 10%.
- Developed an end-to-end product up selling model and analysed post pilot deployment performance. On average, increased profitability for every up-sell by \$51.

Data Analyst(Remote)

09/2016 - 02/2017 | Nairobi, Kenya

- Led analyst in the development of machine learning powered vehicle valuation engine (www.carduka.com ℰ).
- Provide deep insights on data analysis and data visualizations.

Claims Analyst, UAP Insurance Ltd

01/2015 - 08/2015 | Nairobi, Kenya

- Processing claims by initiating claim confirmation, quantification and process discharge vouchers.
- Conducting monthly claims analysis.



Technical Skills

Data Tech Stack Python, R, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Excel, Google Suite,

Office 365 Suite, Git, Trello, Jira, Slack

Data visualization and communication, data wrangling, probability and statistics, customer and business analytics, predictive modelling.

Soft Skills

Business intuition and impact analysis, good presentation and communication, collaboration, problem-solving, creative thinking, project management.

Education

M.Sc Mathematics, University of Stellenbosch

M.Sc Mathematical Sciences, University of Cape Town

B.Sc Statistics, University of Nairobi First Class, Honors

03/2017 - 04/2019 | Cape Town, ZA 08/2015 - 06/2016 | Cape Town, ZA

10/2010 - 09/2014 | Nairobi, KE